Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.7
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 32768,
"max_subtitle_chars": 50,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180,
"start_offset_min": 0
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING PRECISION (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and exact conclusion* of the spoken words (including any held notes or extended sounds) or the appearance/disappearance of on-screen text for that specific segment.
*   **Subtitle durations must be short, typically a few seconds.** Long durations (e.g., over 15 seconds) are incorrect and indicate a timing error.
*   **STRICT CHRONOLOGICAL ORDER (CRITICAL):**
*   **Every subtitle entry MUST be in strict chronological order.** The `start` time of any subtitle entry MUST be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the immediately preceding subtitle entry.
*   **Crucially, subtitle segments MUST NOT overlap.** The `start` time of a new segment must be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the previous segment.
*   **Any deviation from strict chronological order or overlapping segments will result in immediate rejection and re-processing of the entire segment.** This is a non-negotiable requirement.
*   Timestamps must always be in `MM:SS` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **COMPREHENSIVE CONTEXTUAL UNDERSTANDING:**
*   **Watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative. This holistic understanding is crucial for accurate transcriptions and translations.
*   **Always combine logical sentences or phrases split across multiple subtitle entries** to understand the full, complete meaning before translating. Ensure each translated entry is a coherent part of the overarching sentence.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals, surrounding dialogue, speaker intent, tone) to infer the most probable dialogue.
*   **DO NOT HALLUCINATE:** Only transcribe and translate content that is actually present in the video (spoken or on-screen). Do not invent dialogue or text.
*   **Include relevant on-screen text:** If there is text displayed on screen that is relevant to the video's content, transcribe and translate it as well, ensuring its timing aligns with its appearance on screen.
*   **Example of Holistic Translation:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **TRANSLATION ACCURACY & NUANCE:**
*   **Prioritize natural-sounding translations:** Translations should read as if originally written in the target language, avoiding overly literal or awkward phrasing.
*   **Maintain cultural appropriateness:** Adapt idioms, cultural references, and nuances to resonate with the target audience while preserving the original meaning.
*   **Ensure consistency:** Use consistent terminology and phrasing for recurring concepts or names throughout the entire transcription/translation.
4.  **DUAL LANGUAGE PROVISION:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue and relevant on-screen text.
5.  **READABILITY & FORMATTING:**
*   Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Aim for natural breaks that preserve meaning.
*   Each subtitle entry (English and Japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters.
*   Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
6.  **REVIEW AND REFINE:**
*   Before finalizing, review all generated subtitles to ensure they meet all the above requirements, especially timing precision, chronological order, and translation accuracy.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
Reversible 風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Reversible - Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
#KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2025
愛言葉Ⅳ 作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Aikotoba IV / Lyrics & Music: DECO*27
皆さん、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025に
Everyone, to Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025,
来てくださりましてありがとうございます！
thank you so much for coming!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy it to the fullest!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never could have imagined
現状 君もそう思った？
this reality. Did you think so too?
“最高”って止まらないように
So that "the best" never stops,
更新したい
I want to keep updating it.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much further to the dreams I want to come true?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has ever gone before,
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
we can't stop until we get there.
たぶんしんどいけど どうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but please bear with me.
ねえねえ たまにメーデー
Hey, hey, sometimes I call out "mayday."
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
Things I can't create on my own.
僕とか君とかあたしとか
Me, you, them,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
crushes, love, all of it together.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind to go somewhere else?
ありえないよ
That's impossible!
君がくれた音に
With the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
with the sparks that burst,
初めましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you since we first met.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us is fine, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to me, even at my worst.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on, the two of us... that's what's best.
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
This story swells with fantasies,
感謝 やけに凹んじゃって
and gratitude makes me feel even more down.
代償 求めすぎはヤだよ
I hate asking for too much in return.
終わんない愛の連盟 どうでしょ
An endless league of love, how about it?
ねえねえ おいでメーデー 僕が君にできること
Hey, hey, come on, mayday. What I can do for you,
まだまだまだまだあるけど
there's still so much more,
驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
but it's a secret because I want to surprise you.
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと 許さないよ
The fact that your love always wins... I won't allow it!
グー
Rock...
君以外はヤダ
I don't want anyone but you.
我儘は
My selfishness is
ただ
free.
変わらないトキメキを
This unchanging excitement...
絶叫しちゃうのはバカ？
is it foolish to scream about it?
君がくれた音に
With the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
with the sparks that burst,
初めましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you since we first met.
君のいない未来考えらんない
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us is fine, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to me, even at my worst.
君のいない未来考えらんない
I can't imagine a future without you.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
これから先も2人で それがいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us. That sounds great.
乙女解剖であそぼうよ
Let's play with maiden dissection.
ドキドキしたいじゃんか誰だって
Everyone wants their heart to pound.
アンドロイドガール をかわしちゃった おかしくなっちゃった
The Android Girl went a little crazy.
痛みのないキスが離れない
I can't forget that painless kiss.
僕らヴァンパイア
We're vampires.
いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
Go on, you can bite me.
「もう無理もう無理」なんて悪い子じゃない？
Saying "I can't" doesn't make me a bad girl, right?
こんな歌歌ったんだって
Even if I sing a song like this,
君が輝けるように
it's so that you can shine.
はい、というわけで
Alright, so...
皆の衆、こんばんはでござる！
Good evening, everyone-de gozaru!
ホロライブ６期生、つよつよかっこいい
hololive's 6th generation, the super strong, cool,
ごううん侍、風真いろはでござる！
lucky samurai, Kazama Iroha-de gozaru!
はい、今年の誕生日一発目は
Yes, for the first song of my birthday this year,
DECO*27さんの愛言葉シリーズ、4、
I performed DECO*27-san's Aikotoba series, 4,
愛言葉IVを歌って踊らせていただきました！
Aikotoba IV, singing and dancing!
拍手いっぱい来てる！みんな、ありがとう！
So much applause! Thank you, everyone!
ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます！
Thank you for the gifts and Super Chats, too!
今日ね、たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど
I'll be singing and dancing a lot today,
感想とか、あとスクリーンショットとかは、ここ！
so for your thoughts and screenshots, right here!
#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025 でたくさんポストしてください！
Please post a lot with #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLIVE2025!
振り返る時に見に行きますからね！
I'll go back and look at them later!
そして、今回なんと
And for this occasion,
誕生日用のステージを作っていただきました！
they made a special birthday stage for me!
かわいいー！
It's so cute!
ぽこさん、お前ディスプレイになったんか…
Poko-san, you turned into a display...
いやあ、どこに行ってたかと思ったらディスプレイになっとりました。はい。
I wondered where you'd gone, and you became a display. Yep.
そして後ろにも書いてあります、今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、
And as it says behind me, the title for this live,
リバーシブルになってます！
is "Reversible"!
素敵なロゴ、柊先生ありがとうございました。
Thank you, Hiiragi-sensei, for the wonderful logo.
こちらですね、みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では
As for this, during yesterday's countdown stream,
ちょっと、ありゃ？みたいな、どんなだろうって、まだはてなはてなの方が多かったと思うんですけど、
many of you were probably wondering what it could mean,
今回これ全編見てもらったらちゃんと分かるようになっておりますので、
but if you watch the whole show, you'll understand it.
最後までお楽しみください！
So please enjoy it until the end!
そして、事前にお伝えしていました通り、今回、
And, as I announced beforehand,
風真いろは100万人記念グッズが発売決定しました！
my 1 Million Subs Commemorative Merch is now on sale!
うわー！いきなり来るよー！
Whoa! It's here already!
というわけで、今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので、ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
So, I have a ton of announcements today, so I'll be sprinkling them in.
はい、風真いろは100万人記念グッズこちらです！
Yes, here is the Kazama Iroha 1 Million Subscriber commemorative merch!
それでは詳細見ていきましょう！
Let's look at the details!
はい、まずは、
Yes, first up,
うみぼうずママが描いてくださった、素敵なアクリルスタンド！
a wonderful acrylic stand drawn by Umibouzu-mama!
風真も一筆添えさせて頂いておりますので、
Kazama has also added a personal message, so...
ぜひ皆さんこちらぜひお手元に取っていただいて、メッセージゆっくり読んでください。
everyone, please get this and read the message.
ポコべえもいます。
Poko-bae is here too.
そして次がこちら。
And next up is this.
パブミラー
Pub Mirror
パブ、パブミ、パブミラー！
A pub... a pub mi... a pub mirror!
すごい、ちょっと言いづらいんだよなこれリハの時から思ってたんですけど。
Wow, it's a bit hard to say. I've thought so since the rehearsal.
はい、パブミラーです。結構大きいです。
Yes, it's a pub mirror. It's quite large.
風真が出したグッズの中で、もうこう硬くて、なんかこの、お出かけ系のなかで、タオルとかはあったけどかなり大きめになってますので、
Among all the merch, this is solid. For outdoor items, we had towels, but this is huge.
あの皆さんぜひこちらもメッセージ一筆書かせていただいておりますのでぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
I've written a personal message on this too. I'd be happy if you'd display it.
そして、そして次。はい。
And, and next. Yes.
ランダムラバーストラップ
Random Rubber Strap
ランダムラバーストラップ。今回は100万人にちなみまして、風真いろは今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいてるんですけれども、そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました。
Random rubber straps. These are based on my original songs for 1M subs!
なので風を仰ぎしとかね、実はなかなかグッズがなかったんですけど、今回のために作らせていただきました。
Like for "Kaze wo Aogishi," there wasn't much merch, but we made these for this occasion.
ぜひね、みんないろいろ集めていただいて痛バとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います。
Please collect them all and use them to make things like itabags.
次
Next!
カードホルダー
Card Holder
昨今皆さんホロカとかね、いろんなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、ついに作りました。
Lately, there have been Holo-Cards and cheki-style merch, so I finally made one.
ポコべえのカードホルダーです。
It's a Poko-bae card holder.
定期入れにしても良し、学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです。
You can use it as a pass case, and I'd be happy if students used it too.
皆のお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね。
Please display your favorite Kazama cards in it.
はい、それでは次。
Alright, next up.
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして、
Here is the full set, it looks like this.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
そして今回購入特典は、はい、うみぼうずママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました。
The bonus is a sticker newly drawn by Umi Bozu-mama.
今回はですね、こちら直筆サインのあの数量限定はありませんので、あの皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね。
This time, there are no limited quantities, so please take your time and buy it.
はい。というわけで100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました。うわあ。
Yes. That was the introduction of the 1 million subscriber merch. Wow.
ドキドキってなんか結構安心しきってるんですけど
My heart's pounding... actually, I'm feeling quite relieved.
あのもうこれだけじゃなくてですね後半もあの告知がありすぎて頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで告知いっぱいありますなのであの皆さん絶対に見逃さないでください。
There's more to come. I had so many announcements to cram in, so don't miss them.
でもうトレンド1位なんですか？
And it's already #1 on trending?
始まったばっかりだよ。いいの？
It's just started. Is this okay?
みんなありがとう。嘘。
Thank you, everyone! No way!
みんなありがとうございます。いや、すごい。
Thank you all so much. Wow, that's amazing.
めっちゃこんなに早く行くと思わんくて皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
I didn't think it'd be this fast. It's all thanks to you. Thank you so much.
で、ちょっとお水飲んで次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います。
I'll grab a sip of water and then we'll jump right into the next song.
お待たせしました
Sorry for the wait.
お水いっぱい飲んだので
I drank a lot of water,
この力をそのまま、全てフルパワーで出力いたします
so I'll use this power to give it my all!
それでは皆殿、次の曲聴いてください
Now then everyone, please listen to the next song.
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat Me with a Big Love
Treat me with a big love
作詞・作曲：つんく
Lyrics & Music: Tsunku
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
そ〜んとこ大事なことよ
That's the important part!
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
わがままでないのよ オトコ
I'm not being selfish, boys!
私わかったの
I've figured it out
寂しがりやだと
That I get lonely easily
泣きそうよ
I feel like I'm going to cry
OH YEAH OH YEAH
一日の間でも
Even within a single day
告白をしたり
I confess my love
キスしたり
or kiss
OH YEAH OH YEAH
一日が大人より
A day feels longer to me than to an adult
相当濃いのです
It's so much richer
相当長いのです
It's so much longer
そうみたい
It seems so!
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
そ〜んとこ気まぐれじゃいやいや
I don't want you to be fickle!
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
ごゆっくりなさって イチワ
Please take your time, it's just part one
みんな知らんぷり
Everyone pretends not to know
「他人の事だ」と
Saying, "It's someone else's problem"
違うのよ
But that's not it!
OH YEAH OH YEAH
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow brings a new,
恋愛があれば 逆われ
a new love that will turn things around!
OH YEAH OH YEAH
大人より素直に
I'm more honest than an adult,
たくさん恋できちゃう
and I can fall in love so much!
I can fall in love so much!
そうみたい
It seems so!
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow brings a new,
恋愛があれば 逆われ
a new love that will turn things around!
OH YEAH OH YEAH
大人より素直に
I'm more honest than an adult,
大きな愛でもてなして
Welcome me with your great love
#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
#KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2025
大人より素直に そばにおいで
Come be by my side, more honest than an adult
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so much
そう見たい
I want to see that
大きな愛でもてなして
Welcome me with your great love
妄想アスパルテーム
Delusional Aspartame
作詞・作曲 : picco
Lyrics/Music: picco
ありえない幻想
An impossible fantasy,
あふれだす妄想
an overflowing delusion
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you
息をするように嘘ついても
Even if I lie like I breathe,
あたしやっぱいらない子？
am I still a girl you don't need?
こぼれだしちゃった承認欲求
My overflowing desire for approval
もっとココロ満たしてよ
Please fill my heart more
アスパルテーム 甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream
あたしだけに愛をください
Please give your love only to me
ああもう無理 もじもじ 恋して愛して救済執行BAN
Ah, it's no use, fidgeting, love me, save me, BAN
ねぇ 好きって言ってよ？
Hey, just say you love me, okay?
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An impossible fantasy, an overflowing delusion
つまんない つまんない 欲が散らばって
Boring, boring, my desires are scattered
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
The love I seek, the lust I hide
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you
Yeah
誰のこと見てんの？
Who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of thing?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Stop being a DD for real, please
かわいくなりたい
I want to be cute
キラキラしてたい
I want to sparkle
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
Praise me more and more, for real
泣いちゃう散々
I'll cry my eyes out,
開けちゃうシャンパン
I'll open the champagne
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to my stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ
Let me have you all to myself
本命なんでしょ
I'm your one true love, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
Support me more and more, for real
飲み過ぎ注意 オーバードーズ
Careful not to drink too much, overdose
クラクラさせて
Making me dizzy,
いつだって
always
ああもう無理もじもじ 上がって下がって執行BAN
Ah, it's no use, fidgeting, up and down, BAN
ねぇ 好きって言わせて？
Hey, let me say I love you, okay?
噛みついた衝動
The impulse I bit into,
戻れない焦燥
the impatience I can't return from
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
Unbearable midnight, our fingers intertwine
ときめいた表情
A fluttered expression,
何も言わないで
don't say anything
君だけがきっと王子様
You're surely my only prince
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An impossible fantasy, an overflowing delusion
つまんない つまんない 欲が散らばって
Boring, boring, my desires are scattered
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
The love I seek, the lust I hide
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you
あたしだけずっと追いかけて！
Keep chasing only me forever!
ねぇ
Hey...
もう待てないの
I can't wait anymore
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you
♡ 404 not found ♡
絶対アイドル やめないで
Don't you dare quit being an idol
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もうずっとずっとずっとステージにいて
So stay on stage forever and ever and ever
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't You Dare Quit Being an Idol
作詞：指原莉乃 作曲：小池竜暉、菊池博人
Lyrics: Rino Sashihara / Music: Tatsuki Koike, Hiroto Kikuchi
私がもし君のとこ 離れたなら
If I were to ever leave your side...
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな？
I wonder if you'd get a little lonely?
意地悪考えてる
I'm having mean thoughts
好きな人はいるの？
Do you have someone you like?
なら内緒にして ねぇ
If so, keep it a secret, please
神様は将来の指輪を
God has hidden
どこかに隠してる
your future ring somewhere
君の好きに合わせたんだ
I matched my hair color
髪の色
to your preference
私の中君だけで
You're all that's in me
過疎化現象は中毒へ
this isolation becomes an addiction
責任取ってね
Please take responsibility
大好きです
I love you so much
せーの！
Ready, set!
絶対アイドル やめないで
Don't you dare quit being an idol
優しい目も真面目顔も
Your kind eyes, your serious face
全て知ってる私が言う
I know everything, so I'm telling you
絶対そうだね 輝いて
That's right, for sure, just keep shining
星は落ちて儚いもの
Stars fall, they're so fleeting
眩しい君が世界一だよ
You, shining bright, are the best in the world
君の夢はなんですか？
What is your dream?
教えて欲しい
I want you to tell me
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't being an idol
覚悟はしてるから
I'm prepared for it
星のない空
A starless sky
それが当たり前で
is just the norm
暗い道に目が慣れずに
My eyes couldn't adjust to the dark road
踏み出すのも怖かった
and I was scared to take a step
そんな時 矢印描く光
That's when a light appeared, drawing an arrow
絶対君は歌ってて
Always, you must keep singing
あの音色ごとわかってても
Even knowing every note of your voice
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
a sparkly outfit suits you
絶対大きなステージで
On a big stage, for sure
1列目でも前で感じたい
From the front row, I want to feel
今日の歌い方
the way you sang today
なんか好きだな
I really like it
（画面字幕）絶対アイドル辞めないで
(On-screen text) Don't Ever Quit Being an Idol
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つこの関係は
Your hard work, my love, this relationship...
強くってもろいな
is so strong, yet so fragile.
推しの幸せを願った
I wished for my favorite's happiness.
だけど でもね
But... but you know...
だって君はアイドルよ ずっと
'Cause you're an idol, always.
初めて目が合った日から
Ever since the day our eyes first met,
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
it's been all about you, today and tomorrow.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please, don't ever quit being an idol.
これは報われないおとぎ話
This is an unrequited fairytale.
恋よりももっと好きだわ
I love you more than being in love.
魔法よどうか解けないままで
Oh magic, please don't ever break.
（画面字幕）UNHAPPY?
(On-screen text) UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man,
（画面字幕）UNLUCKY?
(On-screen text) UNLUCKY?
人為らざる者も
and even those not of this world,
さあまず目指せよ 生きてんだし
aim high, you're alive after all.
目を逸らした過去も
The past I looked away from
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too,
カウンセリング やめ やめ
forget the counseling, stop it, stop it.
ピースピース
Peace, peace.
（画面字幕）UNDEAD 作詞・作曲：Ayase
(On-screen text) UNDEAD Lyrics & Music: Ayase
（画面字幕）UNDEAD
(On-screen text) UNDEAD
ねえねえねえなんだかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, why do I always feel like I'm fighting?
触れたくない 過去の自分自分自分
I don't want to touch my past self, self, self.
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
I'm already long dead, facing a transparent ghost.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
In the depths of childish, painful memories.
残念、もういないのに あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Too bad, I'm gone now. Huh? You like that? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self that's being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Nonsense, an endless label. Yes! It's a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい 巻き付いたまま
I feel like I'm possessed, still wrapped up in it.
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分 死んじゃいない
My former self still won't leave. I'm not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖
It's a chain of you and you.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content with your misfortune.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to even try to be happy.
この世この世は奇々怪々ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会ってあってやっと始まる物語
It's a story that finally begins when we meet.
さあ、一化けしますか 化
Now, shall we transform?
勘定は9倍、ピースピース
The cost is 9x, peace peace.
（画面字幕）Past & Future
(On-screen text) Past & Future
（画面字幕）can't change the Past
(On-screen text) can't change the Past
（画面字幕）Past & Future, run for the Future
(On-screen text) Past & Future, run for the Future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞなんの希望もない
For some reason, I have no hope for the future.
期待できないような気がして
I feel like I can't expect anything.
もう随分生きてる 既視感とテンプレで食傷
I've lived quite a while, fed up with deja vu and templates.
素敵な出来事も気配すらない
Not even a hint of anything wonderful.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
A shame, the karma of my experience
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
A hollowed-out myth and a boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want excitement
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm sick of it, I'm used to it
なんて整っていくガイダンス
Such well-ordered guidance
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
蓋されていくみたい
It feels like it's being covered up
吸い尽くして
Sucking it all up
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
This, that, and everything else tastes the same
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and you
いつの世も過去も未来も
Every era, past and future
現在にあるんだ
exists in the present
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill being alive with honesty
目指してハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy end
死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
I'm not dead, I'm telling you
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ
Don't give up on happiness, be human
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to the suffering
耐えているだけじゃ
and enduring it isn't enough
死んでいるも同然
You might as well be dead
屍のアンデッド
A corpse-like undead
悩める人の子よ
O, troubled child of man
人ならざる者も 強まず目指せよ
Even those not human, aim without forcing it
生きているだろ
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸にヒカルも
To shine in misfortune
幸せに在るのも
and exist in happiness
そんで全部全部お前だ
It's all, all you
過去未来一切合切森羅万象
Past, future, all of it, the whole universe
ピースピース
Peace, peace
Past & Future, can't change the Past
Past & Future, run for the Future
人の在る所に何時も憂い事
Where people are, sorrow is always present
生き抜けこの化物
Survive, you monster
物語
This story
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
ヒビカセ
Hibikase
作詞 : Reol 作曲 : Giga
Lyrics: Reol, Music: Giga
真夜中に告ぐ音の警告
A warning of sound announces midnight
協和音に酔う午前零時
Intoxicated by consonance at 12 AM
あなたが触れる光増す熱
The light you touch, the increasing heat
指先に踊らされ
I'm made to dance by your fingertips
体感 感覚
Physical sense, feeling
静まる夜
In the quiet night,
2人だけの密
a secret just for us two
体感 即感 快感
Physical sense, immediate sense, pleasure
重なる波形に
By the overlapping waveforms
魅了されていく
I am being charmed
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice, okay?
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Love me properly, even through a screen
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound
覚えていてね
Remember me, okay?
私の声を
My voice,
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
and this whole body you gave me
見つめ合うあなたとふたり重ねた息を
Our breaths overlapping as we gaze at each other
響かせて
Let it resonate
音と音と響かせ
Let the sounds resonate
真夜中に問う
I ask in the middle of the night
冷え切った熱
a chilled passion
待ち続けてる
I keep on waiting
午前零時
at midnight
鏡写しに
Reflected in the mirror
飽和していく
it becomes saturated
知らない 音が伝う
An unknown sound is transmitted
感覚 と 体感
Sensation and Experience
静まる夜と 息遣い揃う
The quietening night and our breaths align
体感 と 快感
Experience and Pleasure
錆びたロジック
The rusty logic
「今一度」を焦がれる
yearns for 'one more time'
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice, okay?
次元も超えて 飛ばすシグナル
I'll send a signal beyond dimensions
「ヴァーチャル」だなんて言わないで
Don't say things like 'virtual'
あなたの音にまだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound
憶えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice, okay?
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
This entire body that you gave me
言葉とココロ 熱も願う
I wish for words, heart, and passion
価値観で その息と音を響かせ
With your values, let that breath and sound resonate
あなたの生んだ音に ただ恋をしていたの
I was just in love with the sound you created
苦しみ怒り甘い感傷すべて 打ち鳴らす
Suffering, anger, sweet sentiment, I'll ring out everything
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
Continuously shouting, voices linking
余熱交ぜる 愛、絶艶めく
Mixing residual heat, love shines brilliantly
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
Continuously shouting, voices linking
余熱交ぜる 愛、絶艶めく
Mixing residual heat, love shines brilliantly
魅了されていく
I am being charmed
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice, okay?
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, love me properly
「ヴァーチャル」だなんて突き離さないで
Don't push me away saying 'virtual'
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound
憶えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice, okay?
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
This entire body that you gave me
見つめ合う あなたと二人 重ねて
Our eyes meet, the two of us overlapping
息と音を響かせ
Let our breaths and sounds resonate
あなたの初音もね この声聞かせ
Your first sound too, let me hear this voice
ヒビカセ
Resonate
Reversible いろは生誕LIVE 2025
Reversible Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
はい。
Okay.
というわけで、皆さん、
So, everyone,
新衣装になりました！
I have a new outfit!
どうですか？
What do you think?
かっこいいですか？
Do I look cool?
なんと今回はダンスを頑張ると決めた、その時から決めていた、ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました。
I decided to work hard on my dancing, and since then, I decided to get a cool dance-style outfit.
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆写真いっぱい撮って、撮って、
Everyone, take lots of pictures! Take them,
撮って、撮って。
take them. Take them.
イェーイ！かっこいいでしょう？
Yay! Isn't it cool?
あと、可愛いばっかなんだけど、かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
And it's just cute, where did the "cool" go?!
おい！かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
Hey! Where did the "cool" go?!
じゃあ、というわけで、新衣装になりました。
So, I have a new outfit.
ゲストパートのね、絶対アイドル辞めないでから、あのソロになりまして、アンデッドアリスと続けてお送りさせていただきました。
After the guest part, starting from "Zettai Idol Yamenaide," I went solo, and followed up with "Undead Alice."
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ、めっちゃ頑張って、あの足千切れそうってそう、そういうことです。
I tried really, really hard. When I said my legs feel like they're gonna rip off, that's what I meant.
本当にたくさん今回は、変身のために飛びました。
I really jumped a lot for this transformation.
足が千切れそうです。
My legs feel like they're gonna rip off.
はい。絶対アイドル辞めないでもね、先輩方がそちらにアップダウンも来てくれてありがとうございます。
Yes. For "Zettai Idol Yamenaide," thank you to the senpais for coming and doing the up-and-down movements.
激ムズだったね、本当に。本当に激ムズでしたね。
It was super hard, wasn't it? Really. It was really, really hard.
皆さん一緒に頑張ってくださり本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you all so much for working hard together with me.
そ、そしてですね
A-And...
あの、この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん
After this, I still have many more guests.
呼んでおります。そして、ござるも、実はこの、このカラーリングだけじゃ実は無いんですよ。
I have many more guests. And actually, for me, this isn't the only color scheme.
なので、そちらも公開していくので、皆殿お楽しみに。
So I'll be revealing that too, so please look forward to it, everyone.
それでは、次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます。
Well then, next I'll be singing with a guest.
それでは、ど、どうぞ！
And now, p-please welcome them!
ブラック★ロックシューターどこへ行ったの？
Black★Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
Lyrics & Composition: ryo (supercell)
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめてわたしはもう走れない
Please stop, I can't run anymore
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's pitch black with no light
崩れかけたその道で
On that crumbling path
あるはずのないあの時の
A hope from that time, one that shouldn't exist,
希望が見えた気がした
I felt like I could see that hope.
どうして
Why?
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
懐かしい記憶
Nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Those days that were just so much fun
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
でも動けないよ
But I can't move
闇を駆ける星に願いを
I wish upon a star that races through the dark
もう一度だけ走るから
Because I'll run just one more time
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
With a trembling voice out of fear, I whisper
私の名前を呼んで
Call out my name
夜明けを抱く空
The sky that embraces the dawn
境界線までの距離 あともう一歩
the distance to the boundary is just one step away.
あともう一歩届かない
But I can't reach it, though I'm so close.
こらえた涙があふれそうなの
The tears I held back are about to overflow
今下を向かないで 止まってしまう
Don't look down now, or you'll stop
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in the future
わかったの
I understand now
思い出して強く強く信じるの
Remember, and believe, strongly, strongly
そうよ
That's right
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
優しい匂い
A gentle scent
痛いよ 辛いよ 飲み込む言葉
It hurts, it's painful, the words I swallow
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
動いて この足
Move, my legs!
世界を超えて
Go beyond this world!
最初からわかっていた
I knew from the very beginning
ここにいることを
that you were here
私の中の 全ての勇気が
All the courage inside of me
火を灯して もう逃げないよ
lights a fire, I won't run away anymore
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
ひとりじゃないよ
You're not alone
声をあげて泣いたって構わない
It doesn't matter if I scream and cry
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
見ていてくれる？
Are you watching me?
今から始まるの
It's starting now,
私の物語
my story
忘れそうになったこの歌を
this song I was about to forget
歌うの
I'll sing it
息詰まる世界で駆られて
Driven in this suffocating world
望むは一体何？
What is it you truly desire?
迷い道で
On a lost path
ルールは無視で行きたいね
I want to just ignore the rules
ははは
Hahaha
ちゅぱぱぱぱ は
Chupa-pa-pa-pa ha
Beyond the way / 作詞：q*Left 作曲：Giga
Beyond the way / Lyrics: q*Left Music: Giga
逆らえそう
I think I can defy it
化学反応ね
A chemical reaction
Kagaku getten now
Get a chemical flaw now
もう聞いちゃいないよと
Saying 'I'm not listening'
ぶった斬るならCry
if you cut me down, cry
しょうもない
It's so lame
無理めのQuestion
An impossible Question
八寸Fiction
An eight-inch Fiction
You make me sick and なんなんで
You make me sick, and just why?
I know the way
願っちゃばっかじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it happen
めちゃくちゃにされて変わらない
Even if I'm torn apart, I won't change
Cry
覚醒 Final word
Awakening, Final word
待って Light up アピールなんか構わないわ
Wait, Light up, I don't care about the appeal
「きっと違うです」も聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing 'That's surely wrong'
全てを Get up
Get up over everything
高所までTake me higher
To the top, take me higher
上々 Dream Break 「無理」ってやつこれで
Top-notch Dream Break, you'll refuse 'impossible'
悟られそう
I think they'll notice
科学欠点Now
Chemical flaw, now
もうずっとちゃんと言わないや
I haven't said it properly for so long
それは誰のせい？
Whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう
Let's draw an endless dream
描いて
Let's draw it
願ったまま
Just as I wished
欲しがったままに
Just as I desired
終わらない夜を越えていこう
Let's cross the endless night
越えていこう
Let's cross it
このまんま 焦がれた向こう側へ
Just like this, to the other side I longed for
ハブられて消せないや
Ostracized, I can't erase it
操作なんてもう言っちゃえ
Manipulation? Just say it already
とか運命感じた感受性はいらない
I don't need this sense of fate
どちらも負けない
I won't lose to either
それを本音とブレ 追っていつもNo.1
Chasing that blurred truth, always No.1
そこどけ そこどかせんまい
Outta the way, I won't let you
I'll convey the thought I've arrived at
Yeah yeah!
Shake your body, more and more
Go beyond the way
Go beyond the way!
息詰まる世界でばかりって
Just in this suffocating world
紡いだ言葉を探して
Searching for the words I've spun
歩み研ぎ澄ませ
Sharpen your steps
この一瞬に従っていけ
Follow this very moment
Follow me all the way to the mirror, Come for me for me my heart
Ooh, move, ooh, ooh, move
思うまま夢を描こう
Let's draw our dreams as we please
描いて描いて
Draw and draw
願ったその先が
The wish you longed for
欲しいか
do you want what's beyond?
手を
Your hand
果てない夜を越えていこう
Let's go beyond the endless night
越えて越えていこう
Go beyond, go beyond
このまま 世界の向こう側へ
Just like this, to the other side of the world
Oh, I need your soul for this
追いかけて 合わせた姿 作って
Chasing after it, creating a matched form
Oh, I need your soul for this
もういい子なのはやめない？
Won't you stop being such a good kid?
世界の向こう側へ
To the other side of the world
already started
We'll go beyond the way
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、本日はこのお二人に来ていただきましたー！
So, for today, we have these two guests with us!
わーい！
Yay!
イェーイ！
来ました！
We're here!
イェーイ！はじめちゃんありがとう！
Yay! Thank you, Hajime-chan!
あい、あい、あい、あい！
Ai, ai, ai, ai!
せーの、お誕生日おめでとう！
Ready, set, Happy Birthday!
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
お忙しいのに、お二人とも今日はね、
Even though you're both busy today,
ていうかもうずっとレッスンからか、本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます。
or from the lessons, thank you for being with me.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you as well.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
今回はですね、誕生日で実は衣装が
For my birthday this time, I actually got a new outfit...
衣装が。ストッキングかわいい！
An outfit! The stockings are cute!
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
めっちゃかわいい！
Super cute!
おへそ！おへそ見えちょる！
Your belly button! I can see it!
へそ、やべ、取られる。
My belly button... oh no, it's gonna get taken.
後ろかわいいよ。めっちゃめっちゃかわいい。
The back is cute. It's super, super cute.
やっぱ似合ってる。
It really suits you.
イェーイ！
Yay!
そうなんです。新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね衣装になったので
That's right. I got a new outfit that's for dancing,
これはおそれ多くもお二人を呼ぼうかな、ダンスが上手い
so I thought, if I may be so bold, that I would invite you two.
お二人を呼んでもいいかなって言って、呼ばせていただきました。
I asked if I could invite two great dancers.
え、違う？あなた、あなた方。
Huh? You two.
あなた方です。ありがとうございます。
It's you two. Thank you.
めちゃくちゃ楽しかった。
That was so much fun.
いや、楽しかった！
Yeah, it was fun!
レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただいて。
We worked hard together in lessons, too.
でも二人ともめちゃくちゃ元が上手いから
But you two are so good to begin with,
風真1人だけ「どうしよっかな、これ、
I was the only one thinking, "What should I do?
二人呼んで大丈夫だったかな」いやいやそんなことない。
Was it okay to invite you two?" No, no, that's not true.
うん。めっちゃ踊った。
Yeah. We danced a lot.
で、最高のものができたと思います。
And I think we created something amazing.
みんな、いいものできたよねって多分今頃コメントにはね、「めっちゃ良かったよ」が流れてると思います。かっこよかったじゃん。
I'm sure the comments are filled with "That was great!" right now. It was cool.
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
だって、ベエちゃんと初めてじゃん。一緒にダンスするの。
Because, this is my first time dancing with Bae.
こういう、こういうダンス初めて。
This kind of, this kind of dance is a first.
お揃い衣装だし！
We have matching outfits!
ねぇ！
Yeah!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
いや、ほんと誘ってよかった！
I'm so glad I invited you!
え、よかった！嬉しい！
Oh, that's great! I'm so happy!
いや、2人と一緒にね、この期間一緒に踊って
Dancing together with you two during this period,
めちゃくちゃ勉強になりました、先生方！
has been a huge learning experience, senseis!
いやいやいや
Oh no no no.
そんなことないです！
That's not true!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
No, thank you!
え、またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って
If there's another chance, let's dance together.
ぜひやりたい！
I'd love to!
一緒にやりましょう！
Let's do it together!
やりましょう！
Let's do it!
いつでも呼んでください！
Please call on us anytime!
ぜひやりましょう！
Let's definitely do it!
じゃあ、ちょっとこの記念に、この友情の証
Okay, to commemorate this, as proof of our friendship,
強、強いかっこいいポーズ、写真撮っとこ。
let's strike a stro- a strong, cool pose for a picture.
かっこいいポーズ？
A cool pose?
かっこいいポーズ。
A cool pose.
かっこいいポーズを思いつかない。
I can't think of a cool pose.
なんだ？
What should I do?
What is it?
かわいいや。
You're cute.
かわいい、めっちゃかわいい。
Cute, you're so cute.
ま、いっか。
Oh, whatever.
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいねー。
Everyone, please post lots of pictures on social media!
カシャ！
*Click!*
はい。と言いつつ、
Right. That being said...
実はですね、もう一つお願いがあって。
Actually, I have one more request.
おお？
Oh?
今日この後、今日初お披露目の、
Later today, I'll be premiering for the very first time...
オリ曲が
my new original song.
オリ曲！
An original song!
あるんですか！？
You have one?!
（絶叫）
(Screaming)
そうなんです！
That's right!
え、楽しみ！
I'm so excited!
楽しみだー！
I'm looking forward to it!
どんな曲？
What kind of song is it?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて、
As Kazama Iroha, I want to be cool,
今回はかっこいい曲を
so this time, it's a cool song
持ってまいりました！
I've brought with me!
うわー！
Whoa!
やったー！
Yay!
楽しみ！
I'm excited!
It's cool! Yeah!
かわいくてかっこいいお二人から
From you two cute and cool people,
やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと。
I think I'll get some courage before I go.
かっこいいビーム？
A cool beam?
え？ビーム！
Huh? Beam!
うわー、かっこいいビーム！ふぁー！
Whoa, a cool beam! Fwah!
あ、すごい、なんか、心がなんか、ちょっとイケメンになってきてる気がする。
Oh wow, somehow my heart feels like it's getting more handsome.
ちょっと待って、イケメンのポーズ分かんない。
Wait, I don't know a handsome pose.
こう？
Like this?
いいよ、かっこいいじゃん。
Yeah, that's cool.
わあ！かっこいいじゃん！
Whoa! That's cool!
え、いけてる気がする。
Huh, I feel like I'm pulling it off.
いけてる！
You are!
いけてる！いけてる気がする！
You are! I feel like I am!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
That's good, that's good!
よし！二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで
Alright! I got a ton of energy from you two,
頑張ってきまする！
so I'm gonna go do my best!
がんばってー！
Do your best!
頑張って！楽しみ！
Good luck! I'm excited!
二人とも今日は本当に、お祝いと、そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて
To both of you, thank you for the celebration, and for singing and dancing with me.
そしてこの応援ビームをありがとうございました！
And thank you for that support beam!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
No, thank YOU!
また遊びましょうね。はい。
Let's hang out again. Okay.
はい。じゃあ、それではこの後、新オリ曲を
Right. Well then, after this, my new original song...
初お披露目させていただきます！
...will be premiered for the first time!
それでは、せーの、どうぞー！
And now... ready, set... here you go!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just by looking
ワタシのこと可愛いだけと
You think I'm just cute, but...
まさか思っていないよね？
Surely you don't think that, do you?
ワタシのホント
The real me
知っていてほしい
I want you to know
ホントワタシ
The real me
Passion Passion
Passion Passion Burning
Emotion Emotion
ホントノワタシ
The Real Me
予測誤差の範囲と
Within the margin of error,
不測の事態も動じない
I'm unfazed by unforeseen events.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
Though I wear a prim and proper face,
心は常に青白く燃える
my heart is always burning with a pale blue flame.
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
媚びたりもしない
I won't resort to flattery,
ワタシを曲げない
I won't compromise who I am.
扱いやすいヤツと
I'm an easy person to handle,
思うな
don't you think?
甘く見ると痛い目みるぞ
Underestimate me and you'll get hurt.
それでも
And yet...
ときには 逃げ出してしまいたい
sometimes, I just want to run away.
そんな衝動に
By such impulses,
弱音吐きたくなる真夜中もある
there are nights I want to give in to weakness.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が
Just the tiniest little compromises
積み重なり重なって動けない
pile up and up until I can't move.
大きな大きな可能性
Great big possibilities
失くし 未来を狭めてしまうから
are lost, and my future is narrowed.
どんなに暗くても辛くても後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful, I won't have any regrets.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて
Being cool isn't about looks,
生き方なんだ
it's about how you live.
現実と理想との
The distance between reality and ideals—
距離を縮められたとしても
even if I could close it...
おすましフェイスでいるだけ
I just wear a prim and proper face,
何事もなかったかのように
as if nothing ever happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop,
後戻りもない
there's no going back,
夢を捨てない
I won't abandon my dreams.
らしいとからしくないとか
"That's so you," "That's not like you"—
決めつけないで全部がワタシ
don't define me. It's all part of who I am.
それでも
And yet...
ときには温もりが恋しい
sometimes, I yearn for warmth.
そんな感情に
By such emotions,
流されてしまいそうな真夜中もある
there are nights I'm nearly swept away.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ
Just seeking sweet, sweet things,
求めてしまうような弱さいらない
I don't need that kind of weakness.
苦い苦い経験だって
Even bitter, bitter experiences
ワタシを強くしてくれるから
will only make me stronger.
これがこれがワタシの
This, this is my...
真実
Truth.
とても狭い狭い世界の
In this very small, cramped world,
中だけで終わらせたくはないんだ
I don't want it all to end.
広い広い世界の果てまで
To the ends of this wide, wide world,
駆け抜けて生きてくんだから
I'll run and keep on living!
どんなに険しくて過酷でも
No matter how steep or harsh the path,
楽しんでやるさ
I'm going to enjoy it.
イケてるのは
What's cool...
はい。というわけで、皆さん
Yes. And so, everyone,
ゲストパートから続けて
continuing from the guest part,
新オリ曲「ホントノワタシ」
my new original song, 'Honto no Watashi',
歌って踊らせていただきました！
I sang and danced for you!
なんと風真いろは、
Believe it or not, for Kazama Iroha,
7曲目のオリジナル曲です！
this is my 7th original song!
わー！
Waaaah!
ちょっとオリ曲のジャケットも届いているので
I also have the cover art for the song,
見ていきましょう。こちらです！
so let's take a look. Here it is!
はい。
Yes.
こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲、
This new original song by Kazama Iroha,
7曲目「ホントノワタシ」は、
my 7th, 'Honto no Watashi',
こちら、日付変わりまして
will be... when the date changes,
19日0時よりリリースされることとなりました。
at midnight on the 19th, it will be released.
今回の新衣装にちなんで、こちら、作っていただきました。
Based on my new outfit, this was created for me.
はい。ちょっと今までと
Yes. Compared to my previous ones,
だいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけれども
this is a very different style of song.
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに
You know, I'm always grateful
風真いろはのこと、
that when you talk about Kazama Iroha,
カッコいいっていうよりも、
rather than saying I'm 'cool',
可愛いって言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので
so many of you say I'm 'cute'.
But, hey, I have a cool side too! I wanted to show that, so I had this made. Once it's released at midnight, please listen to it a lot. And with the hashtag #MiteMiteIrohadono, I'd love it if you told me your thoughts. And now, shall we talk about the guest part? Okay, back to it. Yes. For the guest part, Mio-senpai, Hajime-chan, and Bae-senpai joined me. We sang and danced together. Mio-senpai, and Bae, and Hajime-chan, thank you for coming! The song was really difficult, and as for the one with Bae and Hajime-chan, I was so bad at this move.
いや、カッコいいとこもあるんだよっていうのを伝えたくて作らせていただきました。こちらぜひ0時にリリースされたら、たくさん聞いて、またハッシュタグの見てみていろは殿で感想とか教えていただけたら嬉しいです。そしてそして、ゲストパートについてもお話ししていきますかね。じゃ、戻ってはい。ゲストでね、みお先輩と、そして、はじめちゃん、べー先輩と一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました。みお先輩、そして、べーね、そしてはじめちゃん、来てくれて、ありがとう！もう本当に歌も難しかったし、うん、べー、べーねとはじめちゃんのやつに関しては、もうこれができなさすぎて
これができなさすぎて
I was so bad at this move,
一生やりすぎて
I practiced it so much,
あの、一生腰痛を抱えて
that I ended up with a constant backache.
これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
This was the cause of my muscle soreness.
はい。でも、すごい一緒に
Yes. But being able to
歌って踊らせていただきまして、
sing and dance with them,
とってもとってもいい経験になりました。
was such a wonderful experience.
皆さん、ありがとうございました。
Everyone, thank you so much.
じゃあ、次の曲に行く前に、
Okay, before we go to the next song,
お水飲んでいいですか？
may I have some water?
お水飲みます。
I'm gonna drink some water.
お水。
Water.
ロゴも見て、実は変わってた。
Look at the logo. It actually changed.
よし。
Alright.
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
息整えて...
Catching my breath...
はい。次の曲なんですけれども、
Yes. About the next song,
やっぱり、みんなバラードも好きだよって
many of you have said
言ってくれる方が多いので
that you like my ballads.
今回の...
So this time...
誕生日ライブ、バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
For my birthday live, I brought a ballad that I wanted to sing.
はい。
Yes.
ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか色々練習したんですけど、
I practiced a lot to see if I could sing it in a cool way.
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので、
I'll be singing it with all my heart,
聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you'd listen.
それでは、次の曲、お聴きください。
Well then, please listen to the next song.
W/X/Y
作詞・作曲：Tani Yuuki
Lyrics & Music: Tani Yuuki
垂れ流した
The TV left on,
テレビの音
its sound filling the room
溜めてしまった
The laundry I let pile up,
洗濯物は今日こそ
I'll finally do it today
晴れでも会えて
Even if it's sunny, let's meet
外には出ないでいよう
but let's not go outside
映えないスナックと
With some simple snacks
アルコールで乾杯をしよう
and drinks, let's have a toast
2人 酸いも甘いも
The two of us, even if the sweet and sour
噛み合わないとしても
don't quite match
お互い寄り添うように
Let's try shifting a little
少しずらしてみようよ
so we can be closer
君がくれた太陽
The sun you gave me,
月で隠れないよう
so the moon won't hide it
輝き絶やさぬように
I'll keep it shining
歌うメロディ
This melody I sing
戯れる Slowly flowing day
A playful, slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond 'I love you'
似た者同士
We're two of a kind
こうして
Like this,
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
I want to laugh until we're old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの
Following the trail of clothes
足跡辿ると
you've left lying around
不意をついて
I'll take you by surprise
後ろから抱きつくの
and hug you from behind
つい、繰り返すと
When we do this over and over,
忘れてしまいそうになるよ
I start to feel like I might forget
振り返ると
When I look back,
日々が当たり前じゃないこと
I see our days are not a given
2人対の細胞
Our two paired cells,
絡み合う特別を
this special connection
噛み締めて生きたいと思った
I wanted to live my life savoring it
まどろみ抱く正午
Embracing a doze at noon
吐息漏れた体温
The warmth from your sigh,
微塵も逃さないよう
I won't let a single speck escape
頭の中刻む甘いメモリ
A sweet memory engraved in my mind
戯れる Slowly flowing day
A playful, slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond 'I love you'
違う者同士
Though we're different,
こうして 年老いるまで
let's be like this until we're old
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
I want to keep laughing until we're old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, Fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning callで
I'll wake you with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手は離さないでいて
Please don't let go of my hand
ごめん、これ そばに居たいだけだね
Sorry, I just want to be by your side
抱えた想いは お互い様でしょ
These feelings we hold, we both have them, right?
ほら、あいこでしょ
See? It's a draw
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
We have misunderstandings and mistakes
筋書き通り行かない打診
A scenario that doesn't go as planned
悲しみだって 半分こにしよう
Let's even split the sadness in half
別れじゃない希望
A hope that isn't a farewell
独りよがりにならないように、いつも
So I don't become self-centered, always
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
Without you, I'd still be somewhere
動けないままの僕で
Stuck, unable to move
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to say thank you
これからは僕が支えてくって
From now on, I'll be the one supporting you
呆れてしまうくらいにね
To the point where you'd be exasperated
愛が増していく day by day
My love for you grows day by day
面と向かうとどうしても
When we face each other, for some reason
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I can't be honest, I'm sorry
戯れる Slowly flowing day
A playful, slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
It's gone beyond "I love you"
似た者同士 こうして
Lookalikes like us, like this
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
I want to keep laughing until we're old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, Fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning callで
I'll wake you with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
はい、それではですね、
Yes, well then...
皆さん、ここまで聞いていただきまして、本当にありがとうございます。
Everyone, thank you so much for listening.
はい。こんなに
Yes. So...
歌わせていただいたんですけど、バラードなかなか3Dライブでやらないのですごく緊張しました。どうだったでしょうか。
I sang a song, but I don't do ballads in 3D, so I was nervous. How was it?
めっちゃ、めっちゃ拍手と、めっちゃいいっていうやつが見える。
I can see a lot of applause and "that was great" comments.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
そして、ここで皆さんお待ちかねの、あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います。
And now, I'd like to make that long-awaited announcement for everyone.
それでは、元気に行きます！
Alright, let's do this with energy!
それでは、ドン！
Here we go, boom!
風真いろは 2025誕生日記念グッズ！
Kazama Iroha's 2025 Birthday Anniversary Merch!
出ます！イエーイ！
It's here! Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろしい。
The visual is just so good.
こちらのグッズが販売決定です。
The sale of these goods has been decided.
はい、というわけで詳細を見ていきましょう。ドン。
Yes, so let's take a look at the details. Boom!
回転アクリルスタンド
Revolving Acrylic Stand
はい、まず一つ目は回転アクリルスタンド。
Yes, first up is the Revolving Acrylic Stand.
え、イラストはナルダク先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei.
うわー！
Wow!
こちらですね、あの、こういうことです。
This is it. Uhm, it's like this.
あの、裏表になってるって言いたい。
Uhm, what I mean is it's reversible.
裏、裏表になってる。
It has a front and back.
そう、あのカラライズ衣装とこの新しい新衣装で
Right, it has the Colorize outfit and this new outfit.
裏表になってます。クルクル回せるので
so you can spin it around. Please have fun with it.
ござるのこと回して遊んでください。
Thank you very much.
And next up is this.
よろしくお願いします。
そして次がこちら。
Heat-sensitive Teacup
温感湯呑
Yes, a heat-sensitive teacup.
I just got a sample in the waiting room and tried it.
はい、温感湯呑み。
When you put something hot in it, Pokobe appears.
これ、ついさっきサンプルが控室に届いて試しました。
While I was in meetings and rehearsals,
あの、ちゃんとあったかいの入れると、ふわーってですね
the water cooled down and it turned back to green.
ちゃんとポコベが出て、ござるが打ち合わせとかね、
This is also super cute. It might be the size
あの、リハやってる間に湯が冷め切って
you'd find at a sushi restaurant.
ちゃんと緑に戻っておりました。
It's a rather large, proper teacup.
こちらもすごく可愛くて、お寿司屋さんとかにある
I'd be happy if you could use it.
サイズなのかな？結構大きめのちゃんとした湯呑みです。
Yes, and next is this.
ぜひね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
Iroha Plushie Pop Dance Outfit ver.
はい、そして次がこちら。
Yes, Kazama Iroha's new...
いろはぬいぐるみ ポップダンス衣装ver。
this is called the Pop Dance outfit,
はい、風真いろは、新、
and it's a plushie of it.
こちらポップダンス衣装って名前なんですけど、
I really want you to take it home.
のぬいぐるみです。
It's a Gozaru plushie. Please play with it, everyone.
ぜひ、お迎えしてほしいな。
So, this twintail new outfit...
ござるさんのぬいぐるみです。みんな遊んでくれ。
has become a plushie!
っていうことで、このツインテールのね、新衣装、
Uhm, it's not a handheld one,
なんとぬいぐるみになりました。
but this type, I think? I'd be happy if you displayed it.
あの、手持ちじゃなくて、こう、こういうタイプだったかな？
And next is this.
だと思うので、ぜひね、みんなのおうちにかざーって
Matching Necklace
もらえたら嬉しいです。
Yes! Gozaru's... this!
そして、次はこちら。
A matching version of this is coming out!
おそろいネックレス
Wait, hold on, can I say that again?
はい、なんとござるのこれ、
A necklace that matches this is coming out.
これとお揃いのこれが出ます。
Yes.
ちょ、ちょっと、もう一回言い直していい？
For those of you who don't usually wear accessories,
これとお揃いのネックレスが出ます。
if you'd like,
はい。
you could tie this to the plushie from before and display them,
で、普段ね、アクセサリーとかつけない隊士さんね、
or wear it to events. I'd be happy.
つけないよっていう方も、ま、よかったら、
It's stylish. Let's match with Gozaru.
こちらね、あのさっきのぬいぐるみにあのくくって
So, with that, the full set looks like this?
一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたりとか、
Wow! It's so refreshing.
イベントの時に付けてきてもらえたら嬉しいです。
Yes, just like the live title, it's "Reversible,"
オシャレです。ござると一緒に、
so there are a lot of inverted things.
お揃いによかったらしましょう。
And the purchase bonus is this.
というわけで、そしてフルセットがこんな感じ？
I've come to end this war.
うわー！なんだか爽やかですね。
This time, since there are two types of illustrations,
そう、ライブタイトルの通りリバーシブルなんで、
instead of a limited quantity,
色々ちょっと反転反転がついてたりします。
I tried a slightly different bonus.
そして、購入特典はこちら。
This comes with a reversible tarot card.
この戦争を終わらせに来ました。
On one side, there's Kazama's...
今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで、
uhm, printed autograph and a message.
数量限定はせずに、
楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you enjoyed it.
数量限定とかではないので
It's not a limited quantity item,
ゆっくりね、あの、購入していただければと思います。
so I hope you can take your time to purchase it.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど、
The sales start time is 9:00 PM after this,
ちょっと生配信の関係上ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性のが今大なので
but due to the livestream, there's a good chance it will run long.
生配信中に皆さん、あの、カート見に行ってください。
Everyone, please go check the cart during the livestream.
あ、でもあの数量限定とかないので安心してください。
Oh, but it's not a limited quantity, so please don't worry.
はい。そしてフルセットの特典もう一つあります。
Yes, and there's one more bonus for the full set.
こちらです。
Here it is.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME
PRカード hBD24-054「風真いろは」
PR Card hBD24-054 "Kazama Iroha"
みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚ついてきます。
Everyone's favorite HoloCa card is included!
はい、皆さんよかったらお手に取って
Yes, everyone, if you'd like, please get it.
ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね。
All you HoloCa players, please use it.
遊び方とかあとカードの詳細は
For how to play and card details,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページにてご確認ください。
please check the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME website.
よし。今、台本めっちゃ見た。
Okay. I just read the script carefully.
言えなかったらやばいと思って。
I was worried I'd mess it up.
そしてこちら、一緒に入れさせていただくカードは、
And the card that comes with it
日本語版のみとなっておりますのでご両者ください。
is only the Japanese version, so please be aware of that.
はい。
Yes.
カートのオープンですが、こちらですね、100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ、
As for the cart opening, the 1M subscriber and birthday merch
両方同時なので、皆さんよろしくお願いします。
will both be available at the same time, so please keep that in mind.
ちょっとごめんなさい、生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
I'm sorry, sorry that the livestream is running long.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信を押してすいません。
To the Holomem too, sorry for the stream running long.
はい。というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Yes. With that, I'll have some water.
OKです。
Okay.
はい。
というわけで、あと最後のお知らせとしまして、
And now, for the last announcement...
この後、本編終了次第、ちょっとまた時間がね、確定したら、15分からか20分からかどっちかになると思うんですけど、
after this, when the main stream ends, it'll be in 15 or 20 minutes.
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもございますので、
There will also be a members-only encore live,
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を歌ったり踊ったりしますので、
where I'll be singing and dancing to that song you all wanted to see.
よかったら見に来てください。よろしくお願いします。
please come and watch if you'd like. Thank you.
メンバーシップギフトとか、今日から入ってくださった隊士さんもありがとうございます。
Thank you for the membership gifts, and to the troopers who joined today.
はい。
Yes.
そしてなんと残念なことに、
And unfortunately,
次の曲が、皆さん、このライブ最後の曲となります。
the next song, everyone, will be the last song of this live.
えー、皆さんもう最後は何を歌うかある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが、
Well, I'm sure many of you have already guessed what the last song will be,
改めまして、この度は風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、
but once again, for Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025,
お越しくださりまして、本当にありがとうございました。
thank you so much for coming.
そしてあの、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださったスタッフさんやダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、
And to the staff, dance teacher, and manager who worked so hard to create this,
皆さん、本当にクリエイターの皆さんもありがとうございました。
and to all the creators, thank you very much.
あの、正直、色々あった昨年の年末から、
To be honest, after everything that happened at the end of last year,
ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことがほぼ奇跡、
it's almost a miracle that my voice has recovered enough to do a live.
なんだったら、もう半分諦めかけていたので。
If anything, I had almost given up hope.
いたんですけれども、スタッフの皆さんやファンのかえしさんたちがすごい支えてくださって
I was... but the staff and the Kaeshi-san fans supported me so much,
いろんな方に支えられて本日、実施することができました。
and with the support of many people, I was able to hold this event today.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so, so much.
正直、まだ本調子じゃない部分が多いのは、正直なところです。
To be honest, there are still many areas where I'm not in my best condition.
だけど今日、少しでもこのライブを見て、たくさんの人に元気が
But I hope that watching this live today, even a little bit,
一人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
was able to reach as many people as possible.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯頑張って参りますので
I'll continue to do my best while rehabilitating,
皆さん、これからもよろしくお願いします。
so everyone, I look forward to your continued support.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲。
And so, a fitting song for the end.
皆さん、最後に聞いてください。
Everyone, please listen to this last song.
風真いろは、新オリ曲
Kazama Iroha's new original song,
「君にしか読めない手紙」
"A Letter Only You Can Read."
♪ ありがとう 書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい ♪
♪ "Thank you," if I were to write it, it'd become a daily thing ♪
♪ 重すぎる 私の想いは 最後に伝えるね ♪
♪ These feelings, too heavy, I'll tell you at the very end ♪
君にしか読めない手紙 作詞: HoneyWorks 作曲・編曲: HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHO
A Letter Only You Can Read Lyrics: HoneyWorks Music: HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHO
♪ 拝啓 私を 形作った君へ ♪
♪ La-la-la, Dear you who shaped who I am ♪
♪ 相も変わらず言葉を 届け続けています ♪
♪ As always, I continue to send my words to you ♪
♪ 拝啓 未来で 私待ってる君へ ♪
♪ La-la-la, Dear you who waits for me in the future ♪
♪ 響く音に憂いなど なくお過ごしでしょうか？ ♪
♪ I hope you're living without a trace of sadness in the sound ♪
♪ 不安が無い日なんて 多分無かったけど ♪
♪ There probably wasn't a single day without anxiety, but ♪
♪ 私の言葉 君の言葉 重なって笑えたんだ ♪
♪ My words and your words overlapped, and I could smile ♪
♪ ありがとう 書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい ♪
♪ "Thank you," if I were to write it, it'd become a daily thing ♪
♪ 重すぎる 私の想いは 最後に伝えるね ♪
♪ These feelings, too heavy, I'll tell you at the very end ♪
♪ 君がいる それだけでさ 理由になるなんて奇跡 ♪
♪ Just having you here is a miracle of a reason ♪
♪ ありがとう 足りないのごまかすよう ♪
♪ "Thank you" isn't enough, so to cover it up, ♪
♪ 愛してる ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ 魔法石のブレスレット ♪
♪ A magic stone bracelet ♪
♪ シロツメクサの女王様 ♪
♪ The queen of white clovers ♪
♪ プラスチックだらけの宝石箱で ♪
♪ In a jewelry box full of plastic ♪
♪ ずっと遊べるよ君と ♪
♪ I can play with you forever ♪
♪ 思い出の欠片たち 溢れるこの場所で ♪
♪ Fragments of memories, overflowing in this place ♪
♪ 私の言葉 君の言葉 重ねて笑ってたい ♪
♪ My words, your words, I want to overlap them and keep smiling ♪
君にしか読めない手紙
A Letter Only You Can Read
忘れられる世界で今
In a world where I can be forgotten,
私が選んだ生き方
this is the way of life I chose.
手紙をさ 書いたからさ
I wrote a letter, you see,
この音に乗せて
so I'll put it to this sound.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
"Thank you"—if I were to write it,
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it'd be something I'd write every day.
重すぎる 私の想いは
My feelings are too much,
最後に伝えるね
so I'll tell you at the end.
君がいる それだけでさ
You are here, and just that alone
理由になるなんて奇跡
becoming a reason is a miracle.
ありがとう
"Thank you"
足りないのごまかすよ
isn't enough, so I'll cover it up.
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
100万人記念
1 Million Subscriber Celebration
7月1日
July 1st
MV公開
MV Release
君にしか読めない手紙
A Letter Only You Can Read
風真いろは 100万人記念
Kazama Iroha 1M Subscriber Celebration
「君にしか読めない手紙」
"A Letter Only You Can Read"
7月1日 MV公開
July 1st MV Release
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025